# 嗨喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, I am Wang Gang.
# 最近收到有私信的粉丝在问这个折耳根怎么吃
Recently I have received private messages from fans about how to cook fish mint
# 今天我跟大家分享一下这个折耳根的吃法
Today I am going to share the way to eat fish mint
# 这个是折耳根的根
This is the root of fish mint
# 它这个根上面有很多须
There are many deep roots on the tap root
# 这个须已经被我们去掉了
We have taken off the deep root
# 然后这个根的话可以用来炒
We can stir fry the tap root
# 然后也可以凉拌 还可以用来炖汤炖猪肺
As well as making into cold dish(salad) or make soup with pig lung
# 我们这个凉茶里面就有这个成分
Sometimes we make herbal tea with fish mint
# 这个是润肺的这个折耳根
Fish mint helps with clearing our lungs
# 可以用来炖鸡炖猪肺
We can stew fish mint with chicken or pig lung
# 然后还有这个叶子
The leaf of fish mint
# 这个叶子的话在我们四川就比较多
The leaf of fish mint is quite common in Sichuan
# 因为我们随时在那个田埂上面都可以找得到这种折耳根
We can pretty much find fish mint on farmland any time
# 如果是说运输到外面的话可能你们只能够吃到这个根
Outside of Sichuan, you might only be able to find the root of fish mint
# 就没有叶子 或者是叶子比较少
There isn’t any leaf or very few leaves
# 我们四川这个叶子喜欢用那个辣椒油
In Sichuan we like to use mix the fish mint with chili oil
# 用来把它辣椒蒜辣椒油一起拌 拌来吃
Eat them together as spicy fish mint salad
# 然后这个根的话我们本地有很多餐饮（店）他会用这个根切碎
Many local restaurants will chop the fish mint finely
# 切碎来做烤鱼
Mix the chopped fish mint with fish to make grilled fish
# 味道也非常的突出
The taste stands out very much
# 然后有的人吃不惯这个菜
Some people are not used to the taste
# 它就跟香菜一样因为吃起来是臭的
Because it has unique unpleasant taste for some people, like cilantro
# 如果你吃得惯的话这个就是香的
If you are used to the unique taste, you will love it
# 好啦本期视频就跟你们分享到这里
Okay, this is what I’d like to share with you today
# 拜拜
Bye bye